



Alex Buijs

+316 4048 5702 contact@alexbuijsweb.nl <u>http://alexbuijsweb.nl</u> Haïtidreef 3E, 3563 HC, Utrecht

Profile

Alex Buijs (17-05-1974) is a developer with over 8 years of experience creating web applications. He gains much satisfaction from programming in Ruby. In January 2014 he started as a freelancer, developing web applications with Ruby on Rails. He enjoys using the latest techniques and adhering to best practices. He takes pride in creating beautiful and minimal code. Alex is a team player and is used to work on Agile/Scrum driven projects for larger organisations. He believes in high quality software best practices such as Test Driven Development and Behaviour Driven Development.

Experience

WEB DEVELOPER, DIGIDENTITY, THE HAGUE - 2014/09-2014/12

For Digidentity, Alex contributed to DigiD, the identity management platform for the Dutch government. Among other responsibilities, he was responsible for upgrading several applications from Rails 3 to Rails 4 and improving test coverage and techniques.

Techniques used: Ruby on Rails, HAML, Coffeescript, SASS, Scrum, Test Driven Development, Cucumber, RSpec, Git.

MOBILE APP DEVELOPER, YELLOWBRICK (KABISA), AMSTERDAM – 2014/05-2014/08

For Yellowbrick, a customer of Kabisa, Alex made a cross platform mobile application with Cordova (PhoneGap). The application is basically a single-page HTML5 web application, wrapped in a native WebView.

Techniques used: Rails (for it's asset pipeline), Backbone, Marionette, RequireJS, Emblem.js, Mocha.js, Konacha.js, Coffeescript, SASS, Git, Scrum.

MOBILE APP DEVELOPER, SEACON (KABISA), WEERT - 2014/04-2014/05

For Seacon Logistics, a customer of Kabisa, Alex made a cross platform mobile application with Cordova (PhoneGap). The application is basically a single-page HTML5 web application, wrapped in a native WebView.

Techniques used: Rails (for it's asset pipeline and backend API), Backbone, Marionette, Bootstrap, Coffeescript, Handlebars.js, SASS, Git.

MOBILE APP DEVELOPER, IDT (KABISA), WEERT - 2014/02-2014/04

For IDT, a customer of Kabisa, Alex made a cross platform mobile application with Cordova (PhoneGap). The application is basically a single-page HTML5 web application, wrapped in a native WebView.

Techniques used: Rails (for it's asset pipeline), Backbone, Emblem, Foundation, Coffeescript, SASS, Git.

WEB DEVELOPER, ULTIMAKER (KABISA), GELDERMALSEN - 2013/10-2014/02

For Ultimaker, a customer of Kabisa, Alex contributed to <u>YouMagine.com</u>, a social platform for sharing 3D print designs.

Techniques used: Ruby on Rails, Coffeescript, SASS, Slim, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, Redis, Test Driven Development, Heroku, Git.

WEB DEVELOPER, MALMBERG (CIBER), DEN BOSCH – 2013/01-2013/10 & 2012/04-2012/07 & 2008/10-2012/02

For Malmberg, a customer of Ciber, Alex contributed over several periods of time, to the creation and expansion of the Malmberg Publishing Platform, a new generation of teaching methods.

Techniques used: Ruby on Rails, Coffeescript, Haml, SASS, SQL Server, Apache, Passenger, Capistrano, Git, Scrum.

WEB DEVELOPER, PHILIPS (CIBER), EINDHOVEN - 2012/07-2013/01

For Philips, a customer of Ciber, Alex contributed to the creation of <u>light-collector.com</u>, a social platform for sharing images.

Techniques used: Ruby on Rails, Coffeescript, Haml, SASS, PostgreSQL, Amazon S2, Nginx, Unicorn, Capistrano, Git.

MOBILE APP DEVELOPER, PHILIPS (CIBER), EINDHOVEN – 2012/02-2012/04

For Philips, a customer of Ciber, Alex contributed to the creation of the cross-platform mobile application Lighting Hub. It is used for browsing the entire Philips Lighting Catalogue.

Techniques used: Titanium, Coffeescript, SQLite, Git.

WEB DEVELOPER, CIBER, EINDHOVEN - 2005/02-2008/10

Customers during this period include: CVZ (Diemen), Zwolle Municipality (Zwolle), Radio Netherlands Worldwide (Hilversum), Equens (Utrecht), Ministry of the Interior and Kingdom Relations (The Hague), ABN AMRO (Amsterdam).

Techniques used: Java Enterprise Edition, Hibernate, Struts, Maven, Subversion, Oracle DB, SQL Server, MySQL, WebSphere, Liferay, Tomcat, JBoss, Adobe LiveCycle, Apache, IIS.

Education

Alex received his Master's degree in Cognitive Artificial Intelligence at the Faculty of Philosophy, Utrecht University in 2001.